#### Madonna Niveditha

Phone: +91-9611400915 | Email: maddy12378@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/madonnaniveditha

Gender: Female | Age: 29 | Nationality: Indian | Marital Status: Single | Current Location: Mysore

# **Professional Summary**

US Human Resources Leader, Strategist and Data Science Enthusiast with over 7 years of inter departmental corporate experience. A go- getter with a proven track record of driving growth and results that is both People and innovation centric. Expert in Mergers and Acquisitions, Change Management, People Management, Payroll and Taxes, Employment Laws, Benefits Administration.

#### **Skills and Tools**

- HRIS Systems: Fidelity Investments, ADP, Paycor, Employee Navigator.
- Data Analytics: Excel, R programming, Python, Machine Learning, NLP, Tableau
- > Payroll Management
- State and Federal Tax Mgmt.
- Bonus Criteria Creation and Mgmt.
- > Pay Cost-of-Living Adjustment
- > Talent Acquisition
- Workplace, Handbook,
  Compliance policy creation & mgmt.
- Mergers and Acquisitions
- Employee Communication
- > Employee Conflict Resolution
- > Negotiation
- > Labour Laws
- ATS Proficiency
- > Compliance Management
- > HR Analytics and Reporting
- > Document Management
- > Health Insurance Administration
- > 401(K) Administration
- > Wage & Legal Garnishments
- Legal and Regulatory filings
- SOC Audits
- > Employee On-Boarding
- Employee life Cycle
- > Employee Exit Mgmt.
- Market Compensation Study
- > Unemployment Insurance
- Benefits Mgmt.: Medical, Dental, Vision, PTO, FMLA, Maternal Leave, FLSA, HAS. Workers Comp. etc.

## **Work Experience**

#### **Manager, US Human Resources**

EqualizeRCM Services https://equalizercm.com

(March 2017 to May 2023)



## **Accomplishments:**

- Spearheaded the migration of US HR operations from the US
  Headquarters to India, saving the company over \$80,000 annually.
- Oversaw 4 to 5 new company acquisitions, analysing HR ecosystems, identifying cost and policy differences, and implementing change management strategies and new employee policies.
- Successfully streamlined the company's payroll system and migrated the payroll management system from primitive to more advanced and efficient software.
- Successfully streamlined the company's 401(K) administration and saved the company about \$50,000 annually.
- Initiated and lead several special projects such as employee classification studies, attrition research, surveys, market role and compensation research etc.
- Lead and mentored the HR team including setting objectives, providing support, and ensuring effective team performance for members both in India and USA.

## **Regular Duties:**

- Headed the critical HR and payroll and payroll tax functions for C-suite members, including the founder, Chairman, and President.
- Processed end to end semi-monthly and bi-weekly payroll for over 100 employees.
- Designed and implemented the bonus criteria and commission payouts to the C Suite members that included the Chief Executives, Vice Presidents, and Directors of the company.
- Oversaw recruitment and hiring processes, including job postings, interviewing, and selecting candidates. Develop strategies to attract and retain top talent.
- Developed and managed performance appraisal systems. Provided guidance on employee evaluations, promotions, and disciplinary actions.
- Conducted yearly Market research to understand market compensation benchmarks and implemented internal banding accordingly.
- Forecasted and budgeted HR overhead costs each year, and managed the overheads based on the budget plan.
- Managed company benefits including PTO management, Maternity leave,
  FMLA, Medical, Dental, Vision Insurances, Health Savings Accounts etc.

- Managed several aspects of crises, such as layoffs, company closures, or significant organizational changes.
  Provided support to affected employees and ensure smooth transitions.
- Tracked and analysed HR metrics such as turnover rates, employee engagement, and recruitment effectiveness.
  Provide reports and recommendations to senior management.
- Developed and implemented programs to boost employee morale, job satisfaction, and overall engagement.
- Took care of legal, annual filings such as form 5500, ACA filing, FMLA requirements, wage audits, workers comp renewal, SOC Audits etc. Lead investigator and attender for unemployment hearings.
- Principal contact person for the stakeholders and vendors and primary administrator for ATS, payroll, benefits, tax, and other external and internal systems
- o Conducted trainings on workplace Equity and Diversity, Sexual Harassment Prevention, Compliance Trainings etc.

### **Management Intern**

Course5 Intelligence

https://www.course5i.com

(April 2016 to May 2016)



- Conducted market research on the European market to identify the untapped sections that would provide the company a first mover advantage and facilitate expansion.
- Identified and analysed potential channels of marketing for the company
- o Devised innovative Influencer marketing strategies to improve the Brand Advocacy of the company.
- o Identified and deployed SEO strategies to increase the web visibility of the company
- o Tracked down related marketplaces that the company can participate in and increase its visibility in the market

# **Faculty (Part-time Volunteer)**

Don Bosco School, Mysore

https://donboscomakkalalaya.com/

(December 2012 to December 2013)



- Served as an English and Hindi tutor for dropout students ranging from 15 to 40 yrs. of age from below the poverty line strata of the society.
- Successfully attained a 30% increase in pass rates among 10th-grade students compared to the previous year through effective training and counselling.

### **Educational Qualifications**

Degree	Institute	Years	Criteria for Passing
Postgraduation Graduate Program, Data Science	Purdue University, Administered by Simplilearn	2023 - 2024	Successful Completion of Capstone Projects
Postgraduation Diploma in Management (MBA), Marketing, and IT	SDMIMD, Mysore	2015 - 2017	CGPA – 2.8/4 (Above Avg. Ranking)
Bachelors in Commerce	St. Philomena's College, Mysore	2012 - 2015	75%, Grade A+

#### **Extracurriculars and Personal Pursuits:**

- Reading Find Thriller and Sci-fi books extremely interesting. Have great appreciating towards writings similar to
  Sidney Sheldon's and books based on Sci-fi concepts such as Story of your life by Ted Chiang.
- Writing Poetry and Blogging, few of which are published are available on my official blog page https://oliviangelicablog.wordpress.com/
- Movies & Cinema I enjoy watching, analysing, and learning from cinema that is thought provoking for e.g. movies like Interstellar, Inception, The Matrix etc.
- o **Animal Welfare** As an ardent animal lover, I enjoy spending time with pet dog and tending to street dogs, cats, and cows.